David Petri

434-825-7956 petridw@gmail.com www.davidpetri.com www.github.com/petridw

Profile

I have a passion for using technology to create enjoyable and valuable products that beget an understanding, interest, or experience that wasn't there before. An excellent user experience is often simple and elegant, and code is no different. I strive for simplicity, form, and graceful functionality in all of my work.

Experience

STUDENT, GENERAL ASSEMBLY WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE; LOS ANGELES, CA - 2014-2015

Three months of building four fully-fledged products while learning everything possible about trending and emerging Web technologies, namely Ruby on Rails, Javascript, AngularJS, HTML5, and CSS3. Learned to write modular, maintainable, testable code with an emphasis on test-driven development and RESTful architecture.

IT ANALYST II, UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA (UVA) SCHOOL OF LAW; CHARLOTTESVILLE, VA – 2013-2014

Provided faculty, staff, and students any support required to facilitate their use of technology in and around the classroom. This often involved hardware and software support, video conferencing setup, computer upgrade discussions, and Active Directory maintenance.

Maintained an Identity Finder server and personally remediated any potential SSNs that were found to be stored on Law School machines.

IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST, UVA DEPT. OF MICROBIOLOGY; CHARLOTTESVILLE, VA - 2010-2013

First responder for all technical support calls for the department. Jobs ranged from fixing printers, to troubleshooting hardware, to removing viruses. This was a position that relied heavily on time management skills as a high volume of calls needed to be juggled. I learned to schedule my day efficiently based around the task's urgency, location, and time-to-fix. Good communication was essential as I strove to keep my clients in the loop and satisfied.

PC SPECIALIST, UVA SCHOOL OF NURSING - 2009-2010

Temporary position in which the main task was to assist the other members of the of the IT team by doing the things that needed to be done but nobody wanted to do. Between imaging machines, migrating users to new PCs, and supporting classrooms and video conferences, I enjoyed getting to make the lives of my team members easier while learning the value of hard work and efficient time management.

Education

James Madison University, Harrisonburg, VA – Bachelor of Computer Science, 2009

Skills

- Quick and always excited to pick up a new technology, language, or framework.
- Well-practiced in Ruby, Javascript, HTML5, and CSS3. I love client-side frameworks such as AngularJS, and enjoy quick styling with Bourbon or Bootstrap.
- Experienced following a test-driven development process utilizing RSpec and Jasmine.
- Knowledgable with PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase, and SQL queries.